ANDRES CHOQUE

andreschoque71@gmail.com • andreschoque.com • LinkedIn • GitHub

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a Software Engineer, I bring a passion for technology, business, travel, and leadership. I have delivered impactful designs and web applications while working with CyberZek and private clients. My fluency in both Spanish and English, and my global experience traveling in the Middle East, North and South America developed my cultural competency and communication, which are skills needed for international collaboration. I hold a Bachelor's degree in computer science, complemented by a portfolio showcasing applications built for various clients.

SKILLS

- Languages: English and Spanish
- Code: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Angular, Node, Express, HTML, CSS, C#, Python, Ruby
- Tools: Git, SQL, MongoDB, Postman, Azure DevOps, PowerShell, Selenium, JMeter, Linux, FreeBSD

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer | Multiple clients

Oct 2023 — Present

- Redesigned 10 new webpages for TACTICA Ministries yielding a 15% surge in website engagement.
- Engineered 3 full-stack websites using the MERN stack and PHP increasing brand awareness.
- Optimized website performance efficiency by 50% enhancing overall user experience.

Junior Software Engineer | CyberZek

Jul 2023 — Present

- Integrated BlinkStick API with Ruby for a network status check and network traffic providing a 20% boost for Network Administrators.
- Developed JMeter test automation for API connectivity tests, parallel with an Azure Pipeline enhancing application efficiency by 15 seconds.
- Constructed Selenium and mocha JS test automation for website functionality/performance which elevated application quality by 25%.

Software Developer Intern | Samaritan's Purse

May 2022 — Aug 2022

- Boosted donation engagement by 20% with 4 Angular UI features, driving increased user contributions.
- Improved efficiency by 15 seconds through integration of 2 C# back-end features for API-driven data retrieval.
- Automated drag-and-drop with TypeScript, which improved functionality by 10% for enhanced user experience.

EDUCATION

Liberty University | Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

Aug 2019 — May 2023

- Honors: Magna Cum Laude, Dean's List
- Extra Curriculars: OpenCV Al Competition 2021, Student Government Association Senator 2022
- Coursework: Data Structures & Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Theory of Programming Languages, Operating Systems

PROJECTS

Personal Business Website

Oct 2023 — Present

- Crafted a modern and minimalistic brand providing web services and solutions to multiple clients.
- Provided services to 3 clients improving their solutions which resulted a 25% increase of efficacy.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Launched Freelance Web Services

2023